Juan Sebastián Mendoza Páez

Forest engineer with a passion for remote sensing, forest growth models, spatial statistics, and their practical application to ecological issues. I am enthusiastic about data visualization and building platforms to communicate research outcomes to a wide audience.

Education

Forest Engineering — Universidad Nacional de Colombia Medellín

From August 2016 to June 2023

Misión TIC — Universidad de Antioquia Online

From March 2021 to December 2021

Training in the programming languages Python, Java, JavaScript and web development libraries such as React.

Diploma in Artificial Intelligence — Universidad Sergio Arboleda Online

From May 2022 to July 2022

Introduction to artificial intelligence techniques with emphasis in machine learning methods.

Software skills

R

- Solid knowledge of importing, manipulating, analyzing, modeling, and communicating processed information in this language.
- Ability to manipulate and process spatial data and integrate it with other GIS tools such as QGIS.
- Capacity to build dashboards using shiny package.

Python

Knowledge of basic structures, data analysis and manipulation of spatial data.

Work experience

Remote sensing analyst — Universidad de Antioquia Medellín

Since August 2023

Contribution to the development of algorithms for processing satellite imagery to classify land cover using deep learning techniques.

Auxiliar student — Universidad Nacional de Colombia Medellín

From May 2023 to June 2023

Participation in the data analysis and generation of growth models for four native tree species established as part of "Más bosques para Medellín" project.

Biostatistics I auxiliar — Universidad Nacional de Colombia Medellín

From March 2021 to June 2022

Supporting teaching by offering workshops introducing the R programming language to undergraduate statistics students.

- **▼** jsmendozap@unal.edu.co
- https://jsmendozap.github.
- Medellín
- Colombian
- 3228881349

Languages

English

> TOEFL: 69/120

German

Academic interests

Forest modeling

Remote sensing

Spatial analysis

Data visualization

@jsmendozap